Alright, welcome back. I'm Bobby Larew, your expert on diving. We're in the hurdle phase of our front approach, OK. We've done the approach, now we're in the hurdle phase.
Here's what we just talked about, pointing the feet ant the toes.
Now we'll talk about your legs.
This is a really tricky part, OK.
So I want to walk through both legs.
Remember my take off leg is my right leg.
So when I'm in my last step, my fifth step, I'm going to put my weight on to this leg because the more weight and power and push I get on this leg, the farther the board will go down, OK.
So I'm pushing the board down with this leg.
My back leg, OK, it's a little tricky, is going to come up in to a 90 degree position, OK, or a backwards L, OK.
So, in my hurdle, my right leg, which is my take off leg, is pushing in to the board getting ready to jump.
My left leg is coming up to a 90 degree angle, OK.
Remember my foot is tucked against my other knee, alright.
Now, if you're take off leg is your left leg, I'll do it on the other side so you don't get confused, OK. My left leg is take off.
My left leg and my feet are pushing in to board to get power, to make the board bend.
My right leg is going to come up, still a 90 degree angle.
It's going to look like an L, OK.
Remember, you're right foot now is tucked in to your left knee.
That's what happens on your legs in the hurdle part of diving.